Finding Aid to the Education collection SSC.MS.00446
Sophia Smith Collection
Education collection
1828-1993
1970s
Sophia Smith Collection
SSC.MS.00446
59 boxes (26.5 linear feet)
The Education Collection includes bibliographies, reports, papers, articles, biographies, textbooks, teaching materials, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, conference programs, proposals, scholarly papers, course syllabi and correspondence pertaining to women's education.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Karen Lederer (1993), Pamela Daly Vose (1990), Nan Wiegersma, Setsuko Iijima, and Lucy Therina Briggs. Accession numbers: 02S-34, 05S-03, 15S-29. Accessions were received on the following dates: 2002-07-31, 2003-07-23, 2015-04-10.
Other Finding Aids
OCLC Number: 50490761
Scope and Contents
The Education Collection includes bibliographies, reports, papers, articles, biographies, textbooks, teaching materials, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, conference programs, proposals, scholarly papers, course syllabi and correspondence pertaining to women's education. There are a few original manuscript items. Areas of focus are sexism in education, continuing education, Women's Studies, higher education, physical education, the American Labor Education Service, women's education in other countries, and in individual states. There is a substantial collection of catalogues and other printed material related to individual colleges, universities, and secondary schools from the nineteenth century. Under the topic of Women's Studies, there is information on associations, programs, research centers and conferences.
Coeducation--United States--History--Sources; Women--Education--History--Sources; Sex discrimination in education--United States--History--Sources; National Organization for Women--History--Sources; Minority women--Education--United States--History--Sources; Physical education for women--History--20th century--Sources; College teachers--United States--History--Sources; Women's studies--History--Sources; Women--Education (Higher)--United States--History; Women educators--Biography--Sources; Working class--Education--United States--Periodicals; Professors; Teachers; Videotapes; Brochures; American Labor Education Service; Wiegersma, Nan; Iijima, Setsuko; Briggs, Lucy Therina; Wiegersma, Nan; Iijima, Setsuko; Briggs, Lucy Therina
- GENERAL
  - General, 1970-79 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies, 1927-78 (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
  - Brackett, Anna C., editor, The Education of American Girls, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Briggs, L.B.R., Girls and Education, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clarke, Edward H., The Building of a Brain, 1874 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Council on the Education and Position of Women in a Democracy: "The Education of Women in a Democracy," articles prepared for the round table discussions of the Commission on the Education of Women of the Woman?s Centennial Congress, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Girls? Trade Education League bulletins: "Vocations for Boston Girls,", 1911-12 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - McGrath, Patricia L., "The Unfinished Assignment: Equal Education for Women," Worldwatch Institute, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - National Institute of Education
    - Sex Equity in Education: NIE-Sponsored Projects and Publications, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Conference on the Educational and Occupational Needs of White Ethnic Women, 1978 October 10-13 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - School Review: "Women and Education" Vol. 80, #2, Special Issue, Feb.; 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sewell, Elizabeth Messing, Principles of Education drawn from Nation and Revelation and Applied to Female Education in the Upper Classes, 1866 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Thompson, Eleanor, Education for Ladies, 1830-1860: Ideas on Education in Magazines for Women, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Teachers and teaching
    - General, 1928-76; undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Deans of Women, 1926-29 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Partridge, Mrs. George, Nail Heads: or Helps for Primary Teachers, 1879 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Presbyterian Board of Education, How to Teach the Little Folks, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Stroh, M. Margaret ?Eyes to See? sponsored by the Delta Kappa Gamma Society, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Teacher Preparation for Mothers Who Are College Graduates" a report, Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- BIOGRAPHY
  - Allen, Mary Adele, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Berry, Martha, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Blaker, Eliza Ann, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bragg, Mabel Caroline, 1954; 1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cheek, Mary Ashby, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Clark, Eleanor Grace, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Crandall, Prudence, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Donnelly, Lucy, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Essenberg, Christine Adamson, 1933-39 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fisher, Welthy Honsinger, 1977-78 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fisher, Winifred, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Grier, Lynda, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Hemenway, Mary Porter Tileston, 1899; 1902 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Hillebrand, Charlotte, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Howell, Alice Egbert, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Howland, Emily (Box 4)
    - Letters, 1860-88 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Biographical and photo, 1927-55 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Kingsbury, Susan, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Koontz, Elizabeth Duncan, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Leonard, Emily J., 1889 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Livermore, Mary: What Shall We Do With Our Daughters, 1881 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Lyon, Mary (Box 4)
    - General, 1905-71; undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1847 and Address, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - The Life and Labors of Mary Lyon by Edward Hitchcock, 1858 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - McBridge, Katherine E., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - McIntosh, Millicent Carey, 1947-52 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - McMillan, Margaret, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Maltby, Margaret, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Montessori, Maria, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Palmer, Alice Freeman, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Parker, Gail Thain, 1978-80 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer (Box 5)
    - Letters to Elizabeth C. Lee, 1830, n.d (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Letters from Louisa Davis Minot to Mrs. Gardiner, 1823 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Pendleton, Ellen Fitz, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Sanford, Maria, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Sibley, Mary Easton, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Thomas, Martha Carey, 1901-22 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Willard, Emma, 1828-79 [see also Oversize materials] (Box 5)
    - General: letter, clipping, and printed material, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Emma Willard letter to Professor Coggswell, 10 Jan 1842 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Emma Willard: Pioneer Educator of American Women, by Alma Lutz, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Woolley, Mary Emma, 1930-47 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- SEXISM IN EDUCATION
  - General, 1970-78., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - Publications (Box 6)
    - ACCESS printout on single parents and the schools, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - The Acorn Groweth?, newsletter of the discussion group for sexism in children?s literature, 1973-75 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Beginning Equal: A Manual about Nonsexist Childrearing for Infants and Toddlers, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Bibliography of selected resources for International Year of the Child, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Childcare Information Exchange: manuals on Evaluation/Environment, Parent Relations, and Employers and Child Care, January 1979 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Fact Sheets on Institutional Sexism, January 1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Identity: Female: teacher?s guide to program and fact sheet, and Guide to Women?s Resources: More Than 400 Organizations Concerned With Women?s Issues, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Inequality in Education, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Infant behavioral research: articles and studies, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Minorities: articles and studies about family units, stereotypes, and programs, 1978-81 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Portrayal of women and minorities in textbooks; books and articles, 1970-1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Resource Center on Sex Roles in Education, 1973-76 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - ?Resources for Educational Equity, 1981-82 Catalog? U.S. Department of Education, Women?s Educational Equity Act Program (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Reviews for books on fathers, single parents, and adoptive parents, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Sex Discrimination in Education, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Sexism, consciousness-raising, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - ?Sexism in Parenting Manuals,? article, and Non-Sexist Childrearing: excerpt from book, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Tabs ? Aids for Ending Sexism in School, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Textbooks & Teaching Materials (Box 7)
    - General (Box 7, Folder 8-10)
    - Curricular materials in elementary schools, 1972-74 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Holyoke (MA) public schools, 1971-72 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Kalamazoo (MI) public schools, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - The Liberty Cap: A Catalogue of Non-Sexist Materials for Children, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Non-Sexist Education for Young Children: A Practical Guide, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Observation guides for infants and toddlers, and article on teaching in preschools, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Occupation Simulation Packets: Saleable Work Skills, Project Equality, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
    - Project HEAR: (Box 8)
      - ?Whatcha Gonna Be?,? Primary teacher?s manual and learning unit, September 1976 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Primary, secondary, and intermediate student workbooks, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Intermediate teacher?s manual, student workbook, and learning unit, September 1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Secondary teacher?s manual and student workbook, September 1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Non-sexist reading material, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Overview (Box 8, Folder 12)
- CONTINUING EDUCATION
  - Bibliography, 1967-68 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - General printed material: articles, clippings, papers, reports, and pamphlets, 1962-78 (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
  - "Project Second Start: A Study of the Experience of a Group of Low-Income Women in Adult Programs at Brooklyn College,", 1973 (Box 9)
  - Project on the Status of Education of Women: Publications, 1982; undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - University of Massachusetts, 1970-75 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - University of Michigan, 1980-82 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Re-entry women, 1980; undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Post-college: Articles and clippings, 1924-40 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
- HIGHER EDUCATION
  - General, 1901-72; undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Cartoon: "We're coming, Father Eli...,", undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1860s-1980; undated (Box 10, Folder 3-8)
  - Pamphlets (Box 10)
    - 1800-1979 (Box 10, Folder 9-17)
    - 1980, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Baker, Liva, I?m Radcliffe! Fly Me! The Seven Sisters and the Failure of Women?s Education, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Conference on Undergraduate Education of Women, Cedar Crest College, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "Crisis: Women in Higher Education," U.S. Department of Education Summer Institute, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Doctorates, 1978; undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Entitled to IX, Newsletter of Title IX and the College Student, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Equal Opportunity in Higher Education, Bi-weekly Newsletter on Title IX and Civil Rights Compliance, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Financial aid, 1978; 1981 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Journal of the American Association of University Women, Jun 1939 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Massachusetts Society for the University Education of Women, 1881-1965 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - McCabe, Lida Rose, The American Girl at College, 1893 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Minority women, 1906-75 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Morrison, Martha B., "The Role of an Educated Woman in our Changing World,", 1972 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Opportunities for Women in Higher Education," Report of the Carnegie Commission on Higher Education, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Project on the Status and Education of Women, 1972-82 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
  - Report on Higher Education, U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Mar 1971 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Salem Society for the Higher Education of Women: Reports, 1924; 1926 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Seelye, L. Clark, The Higher Education of Women: Its Perils and Benefits, 1888 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Starrett, Helen E., After College, What?, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Woman and her Community Relationships conference, Syracuse University, 23-24 Jun 1941 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - "Women and Higher Education: An AFT Special Conference,", 11-13 May 1973 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - "Women's Higher Education: Some Unanswered Questions," Wingspread Conference, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Coeducation (Box 12)
    - Clippings, 1963-77 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - B. Currier, "Special Approaches to Women's Education - A Model Coeducational Plan" (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "The Education of Women at Princeton,", 1968-79 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - General, 1883-1978 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Barnard College conferences on special programs for women in higher education, 1979 (Box 13)
    - Individual institutions, 1968-88 (Box 13)
      - Amherst: "Report of the Task Force on College Size and Coeducation,", 1970-74 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Brown (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Colgate (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Columbia (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Dartmouth (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Douglass (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Harvard-Radcliffe (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Holy Cross: P. Shanahan, "Coeducation at Holy Cross: A Dissenting Opinion,", 1969 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Mount Holyoke (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Rutgers (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - Skidmore (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Smith College [see also Smith College Archives] (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Vassar: C. Griffin and G. Langdon, Jr., "Report on Men's Education,", 1968 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Wellesley (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Yale (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Educators (Box 14)
    - "Affirmative Action: Myth and Reality,", 1973 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Association of American Colleges: publications on sex discrimination in higher education, 1971-75 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - H.E.W. publications concerning sex discrimination in higher education, 1968-72 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Higher Education Guidelines - Executive order 11246, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "A Look at Women in Higher Education,", 1972; 1973 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Myra M. Sampson, "Report on the Status of Women Faculty at Smith College,", 1965-66 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Sex discrimination in higher education: Clippings, articles, etc., 1970-77 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "Higher Education: A WEAL Fund Kit,", 1979 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - General, 1970-81 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- AMERICAN LABOR EDUCATION SERVICE
  - General, 1946-61 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - International education, 1927-62 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Affiliated Schools for Workers (became ALES) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - School on the United Nations, 1957-60 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - White collar workshops, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Women's seminars, 1960; 1961 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Annual report, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Bulletin, 1958-60 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Conferences and programs, 1952-62 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Hewes, Amy, 1925-57 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - University of Wisconsin, School for Workers, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Workers Education Bureau of America, 1926-36 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - ?Historical Notes, 1927-62,? prepared by Eleanor G. Coit and Marie Algor (Box 16, Folder 13-18)
- WOMEN'S STUDIES
  - General (Box 16)
    - Articles and scholarly papers, 1964-80 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Proposals and reports, 1971-73 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - ?Women?s Studies in American Colleges and Universities,?, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Anthologies of Women?s Studies, 1973-80 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Fact Sheet on Female Studies, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Female Studies, I-IV, VI-VII, 1971-75 (Box 17, Folder 6-11)
    - Female Studies, VIII-X, 1971-75 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
    - The New Guide to Female Studies, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Handbook for Women Scholars, 1982 (Box 18)
    - National Institute of Education Monograph Series on Women?s Studies, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - ?Theories of Women?s Studies,?, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - The Place of Volunteerism in the Lives of Women, final report for WEAL, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Who?s Who and Where in Women?s Studies, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Women?s Studies: an interdisciplinary journal, 1973-74 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Women?s Studies Newsletter, 1972-80 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous newsletters, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
  - Research (Box 19)
    - Guides, 1974-75 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Research in progress/research published, 1971-79 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Topics: Research News, 1973; A Survey of Research Concerns On Women's Issues by Arlene Kaplan Daniels, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
    - Surveys on women's studies, 1971; 1972 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - New Research on Women at the University of Michigan, 1973 (Box 20)
    - Feminist Research, by Carol Ehrlich, 1976 (Box 20)
    - New Research on Women and Sex Roles at the University of Michigan, 1976 (Box 20)
  - Bibliographies (Box 20)
    - General (Box 20)
      - 1923-47 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - 1972-79 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Women In Cross-Cultural Perspective by Sue-Ellen Jacobs, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Women in specific fields, 1930-71 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Ida Rust MacPherson Collection, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Notable American Women, Library of Congress, 1931-32 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - The Woman?s Collection, 1941-55 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - The Woman's Collection, University of North Carolina, 1941-55 (Box 23)
    - Women in Perspective: A Guide for Cross-Cultural Studies by Sue-Ellen Jacobs, 1974 (Box 23)
    - Women's Work and Women's Studies, 1971-74, Barnard College Women's Center (Box 23)
    - Women's Studies: A Guide to Reference Sources by Kathleen Burke McKee, 1977 (Box 23)
    - Women's Studies Sourcebook, A Comprehensive Classified Bibliography by Judith D. King, 1976 (Box 23)
    - Woman, A Bibliography, the College of Saint Catherine Library, 1967 (Box 23)
    - Bibliography of Sources Relating to Women, Michigan Department of State, 1975 (Box 23)
    - Womenstudy: Guides for Research by Katherine J. Amato, 1978 (Box 23)
    - Texas Women?s History Project, 1980 (Box 23)
    - Women: A Bibliography on Their Education and Careers, Astin, Suniewick, & Dweek, 1971 (Box 23)
    - Anthologies of women's studies, 1973; 1980 (Box 23)
    - In the History of American Women, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Associations, programs, research centers, and conferences [see also Women?s Liberation Collection?Organizations, etc.] (Box 23)
    - Associations (Box 23)
      - Association of American Colleges, 1972, 1988 [see also The Project on the Status of Education of Women] (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Colorado Women?s Studies Association, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Great Lakes Colleges Association, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - National Women?s Studies Association, 1979-84; 1989 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - New England Women?s Studies Association, 1978-83 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Programs and research centers ? United States (Box 24)
      - ?Teaching About Women,?, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Program directories, 1980-82; undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Research center lists, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Barnard College (Box 24)
        - Women?s Center, 1979; 1989 (Box 24, Folder 9)
        - The Scholar and the Feminist Conference, 1976-81; 1984 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - California State University, 1976-84 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Center for Research on Women, Memphis State University, 1989-93 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Center for the Study, Education, and Advancement of Women, Berkeley, CA, 1981; undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - Center for the Study of Women and Sex Roles, CUNY, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - Center for the Study of Women in Society, University of Oregon, 1992-93 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Center for Women?s Studies and Services, San Diego, CA, 1971-79; undated (Box 24, Folder 16-17)
      - Cornell University, 1969-74; undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Douglass College, 1970-71 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Eastern Michigan University, 1977; undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Five Colleges (MA) (Box 25)
        - Proposal and paper, 1971; undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
        - Committee minutes, 1970-74 (Box 25, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence and memorandum, 1970-75 (Box 25, Folder 6)
        - Faculty lists, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 7)
        - Events (Box 25)
          - Women?s Studies Seminar, 1975-77 (Box 25, Folder 8)
          - Lectures and conferences, 1979-84; undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
        - Courses (Box 25)
          - Descriptions, 1970-74; undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
          - Listings, 1970-84; undated (Box 25, Folder 11-12)
          - Valley Women?s Studies Journal (Box 25, Folder 13)
          - Syllabi, 1970-89; undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
          - Course packet, 1972 (Box 26)
        - Degree requirements, 1989-90; undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
        - Training Institute for the Advancement of Women in Higher Education, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 3)
        - Mount Holyoke Women?s Studies Newsletter, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 4)
        - UMass Women?s Studies Newsletter, 1978-84 (Box 26, Folder 5)
        - UMass N.O.W. journal, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 6)
        - Everywoman?s Center (Box 26)
          - General, 1973-75; undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
          - Project Self, 1973-79 (Box 26, Folder 8)
          - Newsletters (Box 26)
            - 1972-75 (Box 26, Folder 9)
            - 1976-90 (Box 27, Folder 1)
          - Miscellaneous events and programs, 1972-1980; undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - From the Apple to the Archive, Washington area women?s studies newsletter, 1973; 1977-81 (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
      - George Washington University, 1975; 1981; undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Goddard-Cambridge graduate program, 1974-78 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Harvard Divinity School, 1972; 1985-87 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Indiana University (Box 27)
        - Bloomington, 1978-86 (Box 27, Folder 8)
        - Indianapolis, 1987-88 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Institute for Research on Women and Gender, Stanford University, 1988-91 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Generations of women in Search of Female Forebears, Jersey City State College (Box 27, Folder 10a)
      - Michigan State University, 1985-91 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Midwest Academy, 1973; undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - New School for Social Research, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Newark State College, 1972; 1975 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Northeastern Illinois University, 1983; 1993 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Northeastern University, 1978-81 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Northwestern University, 1980; 1990-93 undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Ohio State University, 1979-81; undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Old Dominion University, 1982; undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Pembroke Center, Brown University, 1989; 1991 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Penn Women?s Center, 1975; undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Radcliffe College (Box 28)
        - Bunting Institute, 1988; 1991 (Box 28, Folder 10)
        - Murray Research Center, 1988-92 (Box 28, Folder 11)
        - Schlesinger Library, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Salem State College (Box 28, Folder 12a)
      - San Diego State College, 1970-71 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - San Diego State University, 1973-82, undated [see also Box 30] (Box 28, Folder 14)